# Paula Machado de Souza

Front-End Developer
ppmachado.dev@gmail.com
+55 (34) 99154-5970
Ituiutaba, Minas Gerais - Brazil
github.com/ppmachado

### **Skills**

```
• HTML5 • CSS3 • JavaScript • TypeScript • ReactJs • NextJs
```

- Git GitFlow GitHub Storybook Styled-Components Ajax
- Material UI API's Software development Front-end developer
- Figma Adobe XD

#### About me

I'm a front-end developer, based in Brazil but willing to relocate anywhere in the world, with 2 years of web development studies and 1 year on-hand working with JavaScript and other technologies. I'm currently creating a platform, which is aimed to extreme sports enthusiasts, who seek to make friends and map their favorite places to practice around the world.

### IT Experience

Front-End Developer at Roller Map

January 2022 - until today

Responsible for the design and development of the Roller Map platform, which is dedicated to skateboarding and roller skaters' enthusiasts. The design was built at Figma editor and developed with VS Code, using JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJs, NextJs, Styled-Components, Storybook, Ajax, Material UI and API's.

## **Other Experiences**

• 2013 to 2014 – Cashier and sales at Ellus Deluxe boutique (Brazil)

Working with a team of 17 people, improving my teamwork and soft skills

• 2014 to 2016 – Text translator Portuguese – English

Translating academic texts for students and professors

More than 30 customers in Brazil

• 2017 to 2019 – Intern at the Laboratory of Research in Climatology and Water Resources (Federal University of Uberlândia, Brazil)

Working with satellite analysis and documenting heavy storms in the area

Knowledge of ArcGis and QGis map softwares, creating maps

• 2019 to 2022 – Video editor and graphic designer (Adobe Premiere, Illustrator and Photoshop)

Working for content creators, some of them with more than 150k followers

Creating thumbs, video editions and subtitles

#### **Education**

• High School Graduate - 2014

C.E.E.J.A. Padre Moretti (Brazil)

• Bachelor and licentiate degree – 2017 to 2022 (not complete)

Geography – Federal University of Uberlândia (Brazil)

## Languages

• English - advanced

Certified at English as a Second Language – 2013

Richmond District School No. 38 (Richmond, Canada)

- Spanish intermediate
- French basic